Now we're going to discuss the introduction
to the PIMBAC Guide, 6th edition.
So our five process groups, again,
refer back to page 25 in your PIMBock.
That's your process map or process matrix.
Our five process groups are the columns
going across.
Our five process groups in the PIMBock are
a variant.
of the plan, do, check, act cycle created
by Shoehart, later modified by Deming.
All right.
So we'll start our project or phase.
Then we will plan, figure out the
specifics.
So plan, do, check, act.
Planning will figure out how we're going
to accomplish project objectives.
And then we'll keep going through our
planning processes to develop our
baselines, scope, time, and cost
baselines.
Once we are baseline, we'll move into
executing.
That's the due part.
So we'll move into the executing process
group.
We'll create our deliverables, do the
work of the project according to our plan.
Then we check all along the way.
We're monitoring and controlling, reviewing,
tracking, monitoring against the plan.
So we'll check to see if there's any
variance.
Are we off of that plan at all?
So you'll see in monitoring and
controlling when we cover integration.
We, the PM, is overseeing everything.
We'll review track monitor progress
against the plan.
But all of our monitoring and controlling
process is below us.
Again, I'm referring to your process map.
each of those monitoring and controlling
processes will compare the plan what was
agreed upon to data what's actually
happening in executing those are your
actuals so we're going to check we're
trying to stay on top of everything so
that we can quickly take action all right
so we check and act which often leads us
to plan again whether we have to change
our strategies approaches or our baselines
and then we'll go through our processes
again.
Our 10 knowledge areas are the rows going
across.
So we have 10 right just use my fingers
integration scope time cost.
All right.
So each of our knowledge areas is specific
to a topic.
So in the integration management all the
process is going across that row deal with
integration what we the PM will do to
manage coordinate unify that entire
project we're overseeing everything and
that's our focus and we'll have the scope
knowledge area this will contain all the
processes dealing with scope same with
schedule cost quality resources
communications risk procurement and
stakeholder management so those are all
the rows going across.
So again, each row is a knowledge area
specific to a topic.
They intersect in each process group.
So you want to understand where you are in
a process group, initiating through
closing and in a knowledge area to know
where you are.
So integration again is what the PM
focuses on.
That's everything we do to
manage, coordinate, unify that
entire project and how we'll
take it from beginning to end.
I do want to point out, you've got this
little notebook documents that were
referred to as inputs and outputs in the
PIMBock are now called project artifacts.
So I want you to know that they can be
called either.
Inputs, information documentation
key to the process, those
are artifacts that will come
in that we need to review.
Tools and techniques TTs
will be verbs, what will do
in a process to create
an output another artifact.